# **Bipul Kumar**

## Frontend Developer

kb84101@gmail.com

kb84101@gmail.com

**\** 7992312363

in LinkedIn

Github

#### **PROFILE**

As a passionate frontend developer, I am excited to showcase my expertise in building user interfaces for client-facing landing pages using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. I specialize in utilizing React.js to develop highly functional and visually appealing ecommerce websites.

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

### Frontend Developer Trainee, FunctionUp, Bangalore

Nov 2022 - present

Jun 2016 - May 2018

Dhanbad, INDIA

- Trained in Frontend Development using HTML · CSS · Javascript React-JS · Recoil-JS · React-Router-Dom.
- Understanding on Frontend Library like Material-UI · Bootstrap
- Work collaboratively with other team members to deliver high quality work within deadlines.

#### **PROJECTS**

**GYM Websites Z** Jan 2023

- **Deployment Link**: https://gym-website-peach.vercel.app/ ☑
- Techstack HTML,CSS,JAVASCRIPT,REACT,RECOIL,REACT-ROUTER-DOM
- This gym website which allows users to register, login, and purchase subscriptions

Twitter Clone 🛮 Feb 2023

- Deployment Link: https://twitter-clone-1hkw.vercel.app/ ☑
- Techstack HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, REACT, RECOIL, REACT-ROUTER-DOM.
- Twitter website clone with Functionality that allows users to add tweet with images, like and comment on others tweet and can register themselves.

Railway Live Status 🗗 Feb 2023

- Deployment Link: https://railwaylivestatus.vercel.app/ ☑
- TechStack- HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, REACT, RECOIL, REACT-ROUTER-DOM.
- The "Railway Live Status" project enables registered users to easily check real-time train information, including locations, departure/arrival times, delays, and updates.

## **SKILLS**

HTML **CSS** JAVA SCRIPT **REACT JS RECOIL** GitHub Material UI

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor of Arts (Political Science Hons), Maltidhari College** 54.25%

Jul 2018 - Aug 2022 Patna, Bihar

Senior Secondary, KENDRIYA VIDYALAYA MAITHAN DAM 60.2%

Higher Secondary, KENDRIYA VIDYALAYA MAITHAN DAM May 2016 Dhanbad, INDIA

74.1%

## **ACHIVEMENT**

Represented Kendriya Vidyalaya at the national level in athletics, Football.

## **SOFT SKILLS**

Team Player Hardwork Active Listner